# In Sung Jang

312-709-6783, hanlbomi@gmail.com, Chicago https://github.com/hanlbomi

## **Summary of qualifications**

Big data analysis with over 5 years of experience. Proven track record of international collaborations (US, Germany, and S. Korea) and rich publications in academia. Exceptional skills in massive data reduction (>1TB) using powerful clusters (>100 CPUs) in astronomy and knowledge of statistics that can be applied to solve industrial and financial challenges.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Advanced knowledge in programming (Python, LaTex, and IDL), exposure to SQL and Machine Learning (e.g., Scikit-Learn)
- Strong background in statistical modeling and independent research
- Experience in working with large unstructured data sets (e.g., astronomical survey data)

### **Professional Experience**

#### University of Chicago, Astronomy, Sr. Postdoctoral Researcher

2020 - Present

- Applied statistical methods to find signals/patterns in the large source catalogs (N > 1 million)
- Built pipelines to simultaneously process massive astronomical images (Python and IDL).
- Improved flux measuring algorithms; systematic errors are reduced to a 2% level (from 10%).
- Developed linear and non-linear regression routines to analyze time-series photometric data.

#### Leibniz-Institut für Astrophysik Potsdam (Germany), Postdoctoral researcher

2016 - 2020

- Used super-computers to derive photometric properties through non-linear 2D model fits.
- Applied statistical methods to quantify stellar flux above noisy background levels.
- Presented work at 5 international conferences, and collaborated on >10 scientific publications.

#### **Education**

<ul> <li>Ph.D. in Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics, Seoul National Univ., South Korea</li> </ul>	2016
• M.S. in Astronomy & Astrophysics, Seoul National Univ., South Korea	2011
• B.S. in Aerospace Engineering, Inha Univ., South Korea	2009

### **Summary of Publications in Academia**

- 42 peer-reviewed journal articles with >1900 citations (top 5% of Ph.D graduates in 2016)
- 11 first-author articles with >300 citations

### **Accomplishments and Honors**

• Hubble Space Telescope research grants (>200 orbits, \$250K, incl. PI programs)	2014 - 2022
• ESO Very Large Telescope observing programs approved (total 40 hours, PI)	2019 - 2021
• Brain Korea 21 (BK21) Fellowship	2011- 2016

#### About me

I am an academy-oriented person with a strong interest in applying my knowledge to real-world problems.